<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The Bus Abides</title>
    <description>The journey of a millitary transport bus that gets turned into a custom RV. And the people that made that happen.</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jul 2020 19:22:42 -0400</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 30 Jul 2020 19:22:42 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.8.7</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Skoolie Passenger's Seat Installation</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;A school bus is filled with seats. In &lt;strong&gt;trying to save money&lt;/strong&gt;, and make our Skoolie build as easy as possible, we reused a lot of them. However the &lt;em&gt;“idea”&lt;/em&gt; of using a &lt;strong&gt;25&lt;/strong&gt; year old school bus seat looks more comfortable on paper than in real life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/assets/images/skoolie-using-bus-seats.jpg&quot; data-lightbox=&quot;skoolie-bench-seat&quot; data-title=&quot;Our Skoolie originally used the bench seats it came with, cool looking, but a pain in the butt.&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/skoolie-using-bus-seats.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Our Skoolie originally used the bench seats it came with, cool looking, but a pain in the butt.&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We reupholstered the bus seats we reused. So they looked nice. But the padding was still the original foam from &lt;strong&gt;1995&lt;/strong&gt;. While short day trips and even weekend trips were not a problem, long voyages was a different story.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We wanted [needed] to have a more comfortable seat, one that reclines, and has at least one arm rest. Looking online for a car seat can be a real pain in the butt (&lt;em&gt;that’s a seat joke&lt;/em&gt;). Either people want an arm and a leg for a decent seat or they are in horrible shape.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another problem is mounting the seat. Some cheap seats can be found but their bases are designed to be mounted on an irregular car floor. The last thing we wanted was to get involved with welding and metal fabrication. We like to keep things simple.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;finding-the-right-skoolie-seat&quot;&gt;Finding the Right Skoolie Seat&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/assets/images/new-ford-van-seat.jpg&quot; data-lightbox=&quot;skoolie-van-seat&quot; data-title=&quot;New passenger's seat in my 1999 Ford E-350 van.&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/new-ford-van-seat.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;New passenger's seat in my 1999 Ford E-350 van.&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was looking for seats for my &lt;strong&gt;1999&lt;/strong&gt; Ford E-350 van when I came across the perfect solution. On &lt;a href=&quot;https://ebay.com&quot;&gt;eBay&lt;/a&gt; they were selling &lt;strong&gt;NEW&lt;/strong&gt; passenger’s seats for just &lt;strong&gt;$170&lt;/strong&gt;, which included shipping. I purchased one for my van, after installing it I decided to get a second one for our Skoolie.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These seats have a flat base, an arm rest and they recline. It ticked all the boxes. Next step was to get a swivel base. We used a standard 10 inch tall RV swivel base. We have one of these on the driver’s seat and it works well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/assets/images/skoolie-swivel-seat-base.jpg&quot; data-lightbox=&quot;skoolie-seat&quot; data-title=&quot;Swivel base for skoolie seat – always keep a hatchet handy!&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/skoolie-swivel-seat-base.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Swivel base for skoolie seat – always keep a hatchet handy!&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;mounting-a-new-seat-can-be-tricky&quot;&gt;Mounting a New seat can be tricky.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The seat is located directly over the fuel tank, so access to the bolts under the bus, for the base, is a little difficult. We found that the right side bolts could be reached by going through the fuel door on the outside. The left side bolts were access by going under the bus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/assets/images/New-Ford-Passengers-seat.jpg&quot; data-lightbox=&quot;skoolie-1&quot; data-title=&quot;Ford van passenger's seat.&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/New-Ford-Passengers-seat.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Ford van passenger's seat.&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We now have a seat that works well on long drives, and when parked it can be turned around for relaxing. It doesn’t quite reach the kitchen table, but is still MUCH better than the original bus seat. We find it best to make everything in the bus serve more than one function. The new seat had to work for driving as well as being stationary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/assets/images/new-passengers-seat-turned.jpg&quot; data-lightbox=&quot;skoolie-seats-turned&quot; data-title=&quot;New Ford Seat Installed and turned for relaxation.&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/new-passengers-seat-turned.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;New Ford Seat Installed and turned for relaxation.&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/assets/images/new-passengers-seat-straight.jpg&quot; data-lightbox=&quot;skoolie-seats-turned&quot; data-title=&quot;New Skoolie passenger's seats in the forward position for travel.&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/new-passengers-seat-straight.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;New Skoolie passenger's seats in the forward position for travel.&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;our-next-skoolie-project&quot;&gt;Our Next Skoolie Project&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our next project is removing the small wall in front of the seat. We want to install a fold-down cover for the stairs. While driving it will cover the entry stairs which will give is more leg room and block the stairs so the dog doesn’t fall in. When parked we will be able to lift it up. But that project, and blog post, is for another day.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 08 Dec 2019 19:57:32 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/skoolie/skoolie-passengers-seat/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/skoolie/skoolie-passengers-seat/</guid>
        
        
        <category>skoolie</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Skoolie Escape Hatch Replacement</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The Skoolie escape hatch story continues. When last we left, the missing escape hatch was not fixed &lt;strong&gt;permanently&lt;/strong&gt;. We had put something together that would keep most of the rain out, but it was far from a permanent fix.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;gallery-wrapper&quot;&gt;

        &lt;div class=&quot;gallery-box&quot;&gt;
          &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/images/skoolie-escape-hatch-fix.jpg&quot; data-lightbox=&quot;skoolie-e&quot; data-title=&quot;Temporary escape hatch hole cover.&quot;&gt;
          &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/skoolie-escape-hatch-fix.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Temporary escape hatch hole cover.&quot; /&gt;
          &lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;

        &lt;div class=&quot;gallery-box&quot;&gt;
          &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/images/skoolie-escape-hatch-temp-fix.jpg&quot; data-lightbox=&quot;skoolie-e&quot; data-title=&quot;Secured cover with bolts &amp;amp; bungees.&quot;&gt;
          &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/skoolie-escape-hatch-temp-fix.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Secured cover with bolts &amp;amp; bungees.&quot; /&gt;
          &lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The two issues with fixing the Skoolie escape hatch was the age of the bus, and the use of the bus. The navy was this bus’s original home. As such the bus was equipped with things designed for adults rather than children. This meant seat belts, ceiling hand rails and larger escape hatches.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We searched far and wide for a replacement to the missing escape hatch. We even purchased a used escape hatch from a company called &lt;strong&gt;Paul’s Equipment&lt;/strong&gt; out of Ohio. At the time they sold used school bus parts online. Unfortunately the hatch we got did not fit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/assets/images/skoolie-escape-hatchs-side-by-side.jpg&quot; data-lightbox=&quot;skoolie-1&quot; data-title=&quot;Skoolie escape hatch replacement doesn't match.&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/skoolie-escape-hatchs-side-by-side.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Skoolie escape hatch replacement doesn't match&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;skoolie-too-old-for-new-stuff&quot;&gt;Skoolie Too Old For New Stuff&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was able to get some information directly from Thomas Bus company about our Skoolie escape hatch. What they said was:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The hatch you had in your vehicle was an Allied roof hatch. They are long out of business. Their measurements were &lt;strong&gt;21 ¾″&lt;/strong&gt; X &lt;strong&gt;23 ¾″&lt;/strong&gt;. The replacement hatches sold by Specialty Manufacturing or Transpec measure &lt;strong&gt;22 ¾″&lt;/strong&gt; X &lt;strong&gt;22 ¾″&lt;/strong&gt;. There is no ready-made part available to retrofit your hole to adapt to the new size.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was very depressing news. We were hoping to just replace the old escape hatches. We wanted to have them water tight but also give us access to the roof. This apparently was not going to happen. Not easily anyway.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/assets/images/skoolie-escape-hatch-made-by-allied.jpg&quot; data-lightbox=&quot;skoolie-2&quot; data-title=&quot;Original escape hatch made by Allied.&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/skoolie-escape-hatch-made-by-allied.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Original escape hatch made by Allied&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;338&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While we had grand ideas of custom hatches, the reality was we had bigger fish to fry. Because of our limited skill set we decided to stick with materials we could work with. At the time we thought we would like to have the light a sky light would give.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;covering-our-holes&quot;&gt;Covering Our Holes!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ultimately we decided to just cover the holes with tinted &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Lexan-Sheet-Polycarbonate-Thick-Nominal/dp/B004YG6A2S/ref=sr_1_4?s=industrial&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1532200151&amp;amp;sr=1-4&amp;amp;keywords=1%2F4%22+Lexan&quot;&gt;Lexan&lt;/a&gt;. We used &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/3M-VHB-5952-Automotive-Industrial/dp/B00MAQBPEM/ref=sr_1_1?s=automotive&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1532200112&amp;amp;sr=1-1&amp;amp;keywords=3M+VHB+double+sided+tape&quot;&gt;3M VHB double sided tape&lt;/a&gt; and screws to hold down the Lexan. With the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Lexan-Sheet-Polycarbonate-Thick-Nominal/dp/B004YG6A2S/ref=sr_1_4?s=industrial&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1532200151&amp;amp;sr=1-4&amp;amp;keywords=1%2F4%22+Lexan&quot;&gt;Lexan&lt;/a&gt; being UV resilient, tinted gray, and a quarter inch thick we figured we had this project covered. In fairness to ourselves we were just guessing at most of this stuff. So when most of it didn’t work out so well we were not that surprised.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/assets/images/Installing-Lexan-Escape-Hatch-Covers-on-A-Skoolie.jpg&quot; data-lightbox=&quot;skoolie-3&quot; data-title=&quot;Installing the Lexan over the Escape Hatch Holes.&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/Installing-Lexan-Escape-Hatch-Covers-on-A-Skoolie.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Installing the Lexan over our Skoolie escape hatches&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lexan has been covering our Skoolie escape hatch openings for a little over &lt;strong&gt;2&lt;/strong&gt; years now. We installed them in April of &lt;strong&gt;2016&lt;/strong&gt;. Aside from some fading and a few cracks it has stood up well. Fading from the sun was expected and the Lexan is still very strong. The cracking was our fault. When drilling holes in Lexan that is curved it is important to angle the drill so the hole is at &lt;strong&gt;90&lt;/strong&gt; degrees to the Lexan. Failure to do this will result in stresses that can result in cracks radiating out from the holes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;too-much-of-a-good-thing&quot;&gt;Too Much of a Good Thing&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having two large sky lights is great, except during the summer in Florida, where we live. To be fair, we did use the sky lights while we were in Georgia. However our camp site was almost totally shaded by trees. For &lt;strong&gt;99.9%&lt;/strong&gt; of the time we have kept the sky lights blocked!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/assets/images/skoolie-lexan-skylights.jpg&quot; data-lightbox=&quot;skoolie-4&quot; data-title=&quot;Skoolie Roof with Lexan covered escape hatch holes&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/skoolie-lexan-skylights.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Skoolie Roof with Lexan covered escape hatch holes&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Leaking has not been a major problem. Although we did have some issues over the years. We tried different caulk and sealant. The &lt;strong&gt;3M&lt;/strong&gt; tape sticks well but it is not a sealant. After recently &lt;a href=&quot;/upgrades/skoolie-painted-with-rust-oleum/&quot;&gt;painting the roof of our Skoolie&lt;/a&gt; we added &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B002RSIK4G/ref=oh_aui_detailpage_o05_s00?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;psc=1&quot;&gt;EternaBond Roof Sealant tape&lt;/a&gt;. It remains to be seen how much longer the Lexan will last.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/assets/images/Skoolie-White-New-Roof.jpg&quot; data-lightbox=&quot;skoolie-5&quot; data-title=&quot;Skoolie roof painted with Rust-Oleum Paint&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/Skoolie-White-New-Roof.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Skoolie roof painted with Rust-Oleum Paint&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;skoolie-escape-hatch-future&quot;&gt;Skoolie Escape Hatch Future&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that we have completed Phase One of our Skoolie build we can look to making some customizations. What is Phase One? Basically it took the bus from its raw state to a Skoolie we could live in. All the basics are there, sleeping, cooking, showering, pooping, and power.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The plan is to build sturdy metal hatches. Custom designed for the site holes we have. We want to mount things on the roof and have easy access from the inside of the bus. Strength, durability, and water tightness will be the driving forces when we design these new Skoolie Escape Hatches. Make sure you stay tuned and check back to see what we come up with!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jun 2018 20:57:32 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/skoolie/skoolie-escape-hatch-replacement/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/skoolie/skoolie-escape-hatch-replacement/</guid>
        
        
        <category>skoolie</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Skoolie Hump</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;You want the Skoolie Hump! You Need the Skoolie Hump. This hump is what every roof-raiser wishes they had. And we got ours out of pure luck!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;School buses are for children, literally. Which means they are not concerned with height, just safety. Consequently most school buses are not very comfortable for anyone close to &lt;strong&gt;6&lt;/strong&gt; feet tall.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/assets/images/School-Bus-Roof-Hump.jpg&quot; data-lightbox=&quot;skoolie-1&quot; data-title=&quot;School bus roof hump&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/School-Bus-Roof-Hump.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;School bus roof hump&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some of the time, on older buses you will see a hump on the front of the roof of a school bus. This hump is to give the door extra room and for extra headroom for the driver’s area. Not far past the driver’s area the roof usually lowers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;our-skoolie-hump&quot;&gt;Our Skoolie Hump!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/abide-school-bus/&quot;&gt;Our bus&lt;/a&gt; is a bit different. The Skoolie Hump goes the other way. Why this hump is different goes back to the buses origins. We got the bus from a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.govplanet.com&quot;&gt;government online auction&lt;/a&gt;. It was used by the Navy to transport adult people. Because of this the roof was raised. By how much you ask?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;interior-height-of-76-inches&quot;&gt;Interior height of 76 Inches!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That is &lt;strong&gt;6&lt;/strong&gt; feet &lt;strong&gt;4&lt;/strong&gt; inches. More than plenty enough headroom for the average &lt;strong&gt;6&lt;/strong&gt; foot tall adult. I am &lt;strong&gt;6&lt;/strong&gt; feet tall and the bus doesn’t feel low, or short by any means. Maybe that is why we don’t understand why anyone would raise the roof of a school bus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/assets/images/Skoolie-Roof-Hump-The-Bus-Abides.jpg&quot; data-lightbox=&quot;skoolie-2&quot; data-title=&quot;Skoolie roof Hump&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/Skoolie-Roof-Hump-The-Bus-Abides.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Skoolie roof Hump&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/assets/images/Skoolie-roof-Hump-on-the-abide-bus.jpg&quot; data-lightbox=&quot;skoolie-3&quot; data-title=&quot;he Bus Abides Skoolie has a reverse roof hump&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/Skoolie-roof-Hump-on-the-abide-bus.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The Bus Abides Skoolie has a reverse roof hump&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Luck played a huge roll when it came to our bus. We bought is over the internet. We were told it was not running. There was no thought given the interior height. The only thing we did know was that it was missing a roof hatch and the interior was very dirty.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;look-for-the-skoolie-hump&quot;&gt;Look For the Skoolie Hump&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are looking to buy a school bus, we have some advice. First look for the Roof Hump. Try and find a “&lt;em&gt;school bus&lt;/em&gt;” that was not used for children. Most of those types will be taller inside, even if they don’t have a roof hump. If you are shopping online see if you can get an interior measurement. It is almost impossible to tell from photos how much headroom there is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/assets/images/Skoolie-ceiling-handrail-storage.jpg&quot; data-lightbox=&quot;skoolie-4&quot; data-title=&quot;Using our Skoolie's ceiling handrails for extra storage!&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/Skoolie-ceiling-handrail-storage.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Skoolie ceiling handrails used for extra storage&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/assets/images/Skoolie-ceiling-handrails.jpg&quot; data-lightbox=&quot;skoolie-4&quot; data-title=&quot;When it gets hot, we hang fans from the ceiling handrails.&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/Skoolie-ceiling-handrails.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Skoolie cooling using fans hanging for the ceiling handrails&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh, and ceiling handrails are awesome! We use them all the time, and not just to hold on to. The one thing our bus didn’t have was under-floor storage. Because it was shorter, only &lt;strong&gt;9&lt;/strong&gt; windows and has two A/C units there is no room under the bus for storage. But I’ll trade under-floor storage for headroom any time.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 17 Jun 2018 20:57:32 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/skoolie/the-skoolie-hump/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/skoolie/the-skoolie-hump/</guid>
        
        
        <category>skoolie</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Skoolie Dash Repair</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;A &lt;strong&gt;23&lt;/strong&gt; year old Skoolie often needs common repairs. Things like dashboard lights burn out. And repairing them is always a balance between repairing a problem and causing more damage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A while back I removed the instrument cluster of our bus to &lt;a href=&quot;/skoolie/fixing-the-flashers-in-a-skoolie/&quot;&gt;repair blinker indicators and gauge lights&lt;/a&gt;. While the main problems were fixed, the repair resulted in MORE things needing to be fixed. We like to call this the Skoolie Two Step.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/assets/images/Skoolie-Dash-out-completely.jpg&quot; data-lightbox=&quot;skoolie-1&quot; data-title=&quot;Skoolie dash removed&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/Skoolie-Dash-out-completely.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Skoolie dash removed&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Plastics get brittle and glues don’t always hold. When you start digging around in an old Skoolie you are more apt to brake more things than you intended to fix. This is why simple repairs can become long drawn out adventures.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I removed my dash to replace the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/SYLVANIA-Long-Miniature-Contains-Bulbs/dp/B00318V1BU&quot;&gt;small Sylvania #74 bulbs&lt;/a&gt; that light up the dash, I broke some things. Well, I didn’t brake them, they just fell apart. Specifically the masks for the warning lights on either side of the dash fell off. This caused them to slide down out of place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, one of the two screws on the bottom of the dash would not tighten. The “speed nut” that holds it in place had broken and fallen out. I was able to use a wire-tie to keep the dash in place, temporarily. To be honest, wire-ties hold a lot if things in the bus together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/assets/images/Skoolie-Speed-Nuts.jpg&quot; data-lightbox=&quot;skoolie-2&quot; data-title=&quot;Speed nuts for a Skoolie Dash&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/Skoolie-Speed-Nuts.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Speed nuts for a Skoolie Dash&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As usual this repair, of the initial repair required a trip to Lowe’s. We got Super Glue and some speed nuts. I had some &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/SYLVANIA-Long-Miniature-Contains-Bulbs/dp/B00318V1BU&quot;&gt;#74 bulbs&lt;/a&gt; left over which was lucky because I missed a burnt out bulb the last time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/assets/images/Skoolie-International-3800-Dash-back.jpg&quot; data-lightbox=&quot;skoolie-3&quot; data-title=&quot;Dash taken our of our Skoolie for more repairs.&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/Skoolie-International-3800-Dash-back.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;dash back out of a Skoolie&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/assets/images/Skoolie-instrument-cluster-hole.jpg&quot; data-lightbox=&quot;skoolie-3&quot; data-title=&quot;Skoolie dash removed and wires exposed&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/Skoolie-instrument-cluster-hole.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Skoolie dash removed and wires exposed&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With this repair I totally removed the dash and took the plastic cover off the front. I then spent the evening holding things down while the glue set. The old plastic Masks were a little warped and they needed to be held down until the glue had set. Because of the exposed gauge needles I couldn’t simply lay something heavy on them. So I sat at the kitchen table watching TV holding my fingers down on the face of my dash, like a demented keyboard player trying to play an instrument cluster.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/assets/images/Skoolie-warning-light-masks.jpg&quot; data-lightbox=&quot;skoolie-4&quot; data-title=&quot;Skoolie dash fixed warning light masks&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/Skoolie-warning-light-masks.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Skoolie dash fixed warning light masks&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Putting it all back together was its own special form of frustration. There are 3 electrical plugs, 2 specific lights that need to be connected, a oil pressure line and the two air lines. The difficulty increases as you make more connections. With every one you make you have less and less room to work with. Very quickly access to the back of the dash is almost zero.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;skoolie-back-up--running&quot;&gt;Skoolie Back Up &amp;amp; Running!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/assets/images/skoolie-fixed-dash.jpg&quot; data-lightbox=&quot;skoolie-5&quot; data-title=&quot;Skolie Dash fixed and installed&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/skoolie-fixed-dash.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Skolie Dash fixed and installed&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the end we got everything back in. It all works and is a bit cleaner. All the mounting screws now hold fast and the warning lights illuminate the proper message. I think everything is working now, and if not, I’m getting fairly good at removing the dash, maybe 3 times a charm?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2018 20:57:32 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/skoolie/skoolie-dash-repair/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/skoolie/skoolie-dash-repair/</guid>
        
        
        <category>skoolie</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Skoolies Should Have Toilets</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Lately I have seen a trend of people building &lt;a href=&quot;https://thebusabides.com/abide-school-bus/&quot;&gt;Skoolies&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;not&lt;/strong&gt; including a bathroom. The justification for this ranges widely, but it all boils down to ignorance and selfishness. It is wrong, a bad idea and dangerous.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;fastest-way-to-ruin-it-for-everyone&quot;&gt;Fastest Way to Ruin it for Everyone&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More and more people are living in RV’s. There is a big movement in renovating older RV’s and converting school buses. There is a reaction to this that is not positive. This is the limiting of places RV’s can park over night.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This loss of available places to park is a direct result of people not living up to their responsibilities. People dump trash, they over stay at places, and they generally make a nuisance and spectacle of themselves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The fastest way to piss people off is to use the outdoors as your toilet. It only takes a few people pissing or shitting where they shouldn’t to ruin it for everyone else. Skoolies often get blamed for shitty behavior because we are viewed as hippie-types and irresponsible slackers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Skoolie community has an added responsibility to lead by example. It only take a few jack-offs shitting on the side of the road to give us all a bad name.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;there-is-no-excuse-to-not-have-a-bathroom&quot;&gt;There is no excuse to NOT have a bathroom&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you build a Skoolie the investment in money, time, and materials needed to build a bathroom is a fraction of the cost of construction. A good &lt;a href=&quot;https://natureshead.net&quot;&gt;composting toilet&lt;/a&gt; will run &lt;strong&gt;$1000&lt;/strong&gt;, but when you compare that to &lt;strong&gt;$2600&lt;/strong&gt; for tires, or possible thousands in engine work, it is actually one of the cheaper things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/assets/images/skoolie-composting-toilet-install.jpg&quot; data-lightbox=&quot;skoolie-1&quot; data-title=&quot;Skoolie bathroom with toilet&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/skoolie-composting-toilet-install.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Skoolie bathroom with toilet&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The whole point of a Skoolie is to be self-sufficient, off the grid. If not then why build a Skoolie? If all you want is a place to sleep, buy a van. A Skoolie is big, uneconomical to drive, slow, expensive to maintain. Why drive such a big and cumbersome vehicle and then shit in the woods?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It makes no sense to build a Skoolie that has all the conveniences of home except a bathroom. If you include a way to store, prepare, and cook food, then you need to have a way of dealing with food &lt;strong&gt;after you’ve eaten it&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A bathroom doesn’t need to include a shower. Whether you bathe at all is your business. Your personal level of stinky-ness is up to you. Your funk follows you where you go. It is your piss and shit that you leave behind that I don’t want to hike over, or picnic upon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;shitting-in-the-woods-is-the-height-of-narcissism&quot;&gt;Shitting in the Woods is the Height of Narcissism&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If your plan for living or vacationing is to use the outdoors as your toilet you obviously don’t give a shit about anyone else. Naturally there are times when an emergency arrises and there are no alternatives. But if your &lt;strong&gt;plan&lt;/strong&gt; is to shit outside, go fuck yourself. Why do I, and everyone else have to deal with your inability to plan?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This isn’t the &lt;strong&gt;1800&lt;/strong&gt;’s, there are standards that we should all aspire to. The least of which is to take responsibility for our own waste. The proper handling of and disposal of human waste has allowed human society to flourish. Reverting back to when everyone did whatever they wanted, wherever they wanted is idiotic and dangerous.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;having-a-bathroom-is-a-health--safety-issue&quot;&gt;Having a Bathroom Is a Health &amp;amp; Safety Issue&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your shit and piss is not something that should be treated lightly. There are serious health issues involved. There are very important reasons we all don’t just shit in the woods or piss on the street corner. Ignoring these facts is a very dangerous thing to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;not-having-a-bathroom-is-extremely-short-sighted&quot;&gt;Not Having a Bathroom is Extremely Short Sighted&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everything is not roses and unicorn farts! If you have a Skoolie for any length of time you know things happen. And just like your bus, you are going to break down from time to time. Your adventure on the road can be severely hampered by one bad meal, an off shrimp, or a poorly washed head of lettuce.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What are you going to do when you have to shit every 3 hours and you are on the road? You can’t park at McDonalds over night. It can be hard enough finding a place to legally park, let alone parking with access to a &lt;strong&gt;24/7&lt;/strong&gt; bathroom.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are out in the woods, well that will be no better. Try shitting in the woods at night, in the rain, or the snow. That is a great way to turn food poisoning into the flu. If you have a Skoolie your motto should be plan for the best and prepare for the worst.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You should travel with a tool kit, extra fuses, flash lights, extra coolant and oil, a tow strap &lt;strong&gt;and a place to put your shit&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;em&gt;literally&lt;/em&gt;)!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/assets/images/Skoolie-full-bathroom.jpg&quot; data-lightbox=&quot;skoolie-2&quot; data-title=&quot;Our Skoolie is only a 9 window bus but we found enough space for a full bathroom.&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/Skoolie-full-bathroom.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Our Skoolie is only a 9 window bus but we found enough space for a full bathroom.&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;bottom-line-on-your-bottom&quot;&gt;Bottom Line on Your Bottom&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you travel you should be taking only pictures and leaving only foot prints. You pack-out everything you pack-in. Being responsible for your waste, however generated, is part of the spirit behind building a Skoolie. Recycle and reuse, making the most of what you have, and not just having the most. Living simply and healthily.&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-converted-space&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/assets/images/skoolie-bath-fancy-bathroom.jpg&quot; data-lightbox=&quot;skoolie-3&quot; data-title=&quot;A nice bathroom so clean even the Virgin Mary herself would be proud to take a dump in.&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/skoolie-bath-fancy-bathroom.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A nice bathroom so clean even the Virgin Mary herself would be proud to take a dump in.&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is not being a free spirit, or doing your own thing, to &lt;strong&gt;NOT&lt;/strong&gt; have a bathroom in your Skoolie. It is irresponsible, shortsighted, dangerous, narcissistic, and ultimately will ruin a good thing for everyone.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 29 Apr 2018 20:57:32 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/plumbing/skoolies-should-have-bathrooms/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/plumbing/skoolies-should-have-bathrooms/</guid>
        
        
        <category>plumbing</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Skoolie Painted with Rust-Oleum</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Rust-Oleum paint is fine for painting a Skoolie. However there is a lot of differing information out there about how to go about it. Painting a Skoolie is not rocket science.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our &lt;a href=&quot;https://thebusabides.com/abide-school-bus/&quot;&gt;Skoolie is a &lt;strong&gt;1995&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and it spent the vast majority of its time in the Navy, stationed in south Georgia. We live in southwest Florida so the roof of our bus has seen plenty of sun.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because the bus was in the Navy it was originally white. We are happy to keep that color on the roof, all our vehicles are white. It is a must in our book to keep things as cool as possible in the summer. White is a hard color for a vehicle as it shows all the dirt. But we are willing to trade that for a cooler vehicle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the years the sun has turned the roof paint to chalk. Couple that with some surface rust and a few rusty rivets and it was time for a paint job. We got estimates from a bunch of places. The cheapest was &lt;strong&gt;$4000&lt;/strong&gt;, just for the roof! The most expensive was &lt;strong&gt;$6000&lt;/strong&gt; to &lt;a href=&quot;http://linexswfl.com&quot;&gt;Line-X&lt;/a&gt; the roof.&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-converted-space&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://linexswfl.com&quot;&gt;Line-X&lt;/a&gt; would have been great for sealing the roof and giving a little thermal protection. But we were told that white &lt;a href=&quot;http://linexswfl.com&quot;&gt;Line-X&lt;/a&gt; was possible, but it not recommended. They suggested using a color, any color other than white. Another reason we didn’t go with &lt;a href=&quot;http://linexswfl.com&quot;&gt;Line-X&lt;/a&gt; was that it has a definite texture. Washing the roof of the bus is hard enough without adding texture to the mix.&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-converted-space&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Southwest Florida is hot and wet. By the end of the summer the bus, the house and my truck are all turning green. Coming from New England growing algae on a vehicle was never an issue. The texture of &lt;a href=&quot;http://linexswfl.com&quot;&gt;Line-X&lt;/a&gt; was just going to give a lot of small places for our bus to turn green.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/assets/images/Skoolie-Roof-before-paint.jpg&quot; data-lightbox=&quot;skoolie-1&quot; data-title=&quot;The paint on the roof was like chalk, it sanded off every easy.&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/Skoolie-Roof-before-paint.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The paint on the roof was like chalk, it sanded off every easy.&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;painting-a-skoolie-with-a-roller&quot;&gt;Painting a Skoolie with a Roller&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was decided that we would paint the roof ourselves. Further research, and looking at the bank account, resulted in the choice of paint. One gallon of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.homedepot.com/p/Rust-Oleum-Professional-1-gal-White-Gloss-Protective-Enamel-Case-of-2-K7792402/202058442&quot;&gt;Rust-Oleum in bright white&lt;/a&gt;. We got some rollers, cheap brushes, pan liners, tape and sandpaper at Home Depot and we were off.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;gallery-wrapper&quot;&gt;

        &lt;div class=&quot;gallery-box&quot;&gt;
          &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/images/Skoolie-sanding-the-front.jpg&quot; data-lightbox=&quot;skoolie-painting&quot; data-title=&quot;Sanding the front of the Skoolie above the windshield was not easy.&quot;&gt;
          &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/Skoolie-sanding-the-front.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Sanding the front of the Skoolie above the windshield was not easy.&quot; /&gt;
          &lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;

        &lt;div class=&quot;gallery-box&quot;&gt;
          &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/images/Skoolie-and-scafolding.jpg&quot; data-lightbox=&quot;skoolie-painting&quot; data-title=&quot;The scaffolding was a great help, we only taped off the back of the bus.&quot;&gt;
          &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/Skoolie-and-scafolding.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The scaffolding was a great help, we only taped off the back of the bus.&quot; /&gt;
          &lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;

        &lt;div class=&quot;gallery-box&quot;&gt;
          &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/images/Sanding-Skoolie-roof.jpg&quot; data-lightbox=&quot;skoolie-painting&quot; data-title=&quot;The scaffolding made sanding the roof a lot easier and quicker.&quot;&gt;
          &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/Sanding-Skoolie-roof.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The scaffolding made sanding the roof a lot easier and quicker.&quot; /&gt;
          &lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Two people sanded while one person (&lt;em&gt;me&lt;/em&gt;) removed all the marker lights. I had purchased all the marker lights (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B000NDD9ES/ref=oh_aui_detailpage_o02_s00?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;psc=1&quot;&gt;orange&lt;/a&gt; &amp;amp; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B000NDM9FI/ref=oh_aui_detailpage_o03_s00?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;psc=1&quot;&gt;red&lt;/a&gt;) and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B00JRE38EA/ref=oh_aui_detailpage_o09_s00?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;psc=1&quot;&gt;LED bulbs&lt;/a&gt; off Amazon. This was the perfect time to install the new lights. The roof paint was mostly chalk and sanded off easily. All we were looking to do was remove the loose stuff. If the sander sat for a second in the same spot you would hit bare metal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The Weather Didn’t Help&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We were promised clear cool weather, what we got was cool rainy days and hot windy days. Working around the weather was a challenge, the plan had to be fluid. The original &lt;strong&gt;2&lt;/strong&gt; day plan morphed into a &lt;strong&gt;3&lt;/strong&gt; day plan. The best investment we made was renting a section of scaffolding. It was only &lt;strong&gt;$50&lt;/strong&gt; for a week and it made things much easier.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/assets/images/Skoolie-rolling-roof-paint.jpg&quot; data-lightbox=&quot;skoolie-2&quot; data-title=&quot;Roll painting a Skoolie with Rust-Oleum&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/Skoolie-rolling-roof-paint.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Roll painting a Skoolie with Rust-Oleum&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The roof was sanded and then washed with dish soap. The caulking around our emergency escape hatch sky lights was removed and the areas cleaned. We wiped down the whole thing with acetone. Then we started painting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We didn’t mask off anything! We figured the bus is white, if we dribble white on white who cares. Drips on the glass can be scraped off later. We set the scaffolding up in one spot and moved the bus around the scaffolding. While the scaffolding was great, it took &lt;strong&gt;2&lt;/strong&gt; strong people to move it. Over the &lt;strong&gt;3&lt;/strong&gt; days we took to paint the bus we didn’t always have the manpower to move the scaffolding. So the bus moved instead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;do-not-thin-rust-oleum-paint&quot;&gt;Do Not Thin Rust-Oleum Paint&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The instructions on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.homedepot.com/p/Rust-Oleum-Professional-1-gal-White-Gloss-Protective-Enamel-Case-of-2-K7792402/202058442&quot;&gt;Rust-Oleum&lt;/a&gt; can states that thinning is &lt;strong&gt;NOT&lt;/strong&gt; required. We were rolling it on, the temperatures were in the upper &lt;strong&gt;70’s&lt;/strong&gt; with low humidity, so no additives were required. It went on smooth and thick. Because it was white over white it seemed to cover very well. Some areas, bare metal and rusty areas that were treated got &lt;strong&gt;2&lt;/strong&gt; coats of paint. The rest of the roof got just one coat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/assets/images/Skoolie-White-New-Roof.jpg&quot; data-lightbox=&quot;skoolie-3&quot; data-title=&quot;The roof looked great after a fresh coat of Rust-O-leum Paint.&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/Skoolie-White-New-Roof.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The roof looked great after a fresh coat of Rust-O-leum Paint.&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are amazed at the results. One gallon of paint covered the roof just fine. The finish was smooth, however we could have improved on that with sponge rollers. The paint has a shine and washes clean 1000 times easier than before. The color is not a &lt;strong&gt;100%&lt;/strong&gt; match to the white of the rest of the bus but we are okay with that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/assets/images/Skoolie-New-Painted-roof.jpg&quot; data-lightbox=&quot;skoolie-4&quot; data-title=&quot;There was a little texture in the paint left by the roller, next time we will use foam rollers.&quot;&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter wp-image-455&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/Skoolie-New-Painted-roof.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;There was a little texture in the paint left by the roller, next time we will use foam rollers.&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We resealed the escape hatch sky lights with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/EternaBond-WHITE-Mobile-Rubber-Repair/dp/B00AYPCJ9G/ref=sr_1_3?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1524798816&amp;amp;sr=8-3&amp;amp;keywords=eternabond+tape&quot;&gt;EternaBond tape&lt;/a&gt;. Then we installed the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B000NDD9ES/ref=oh_aui_detailpage_o02_s00?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;psc=1&quot;&gt;new marker lights&lt;/a&gt; with the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B00JRE38EA/ref=oh_aui_detailpage_o09_s00?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;psc=1&quot;&gt;LED bulbs&lt;/a&gt;. So far everything seems to be water tight. And the paint seems to be holding up to the sun and rain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/assets/images/Ester-rides-a-Skoolie.jpg&quot; data-lightbox=&quot;skoolie-5&quot; data-title=&quot;We had to apply new Eterna-Bond take around the Lexan Skylites after the paint was dry.&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/Ester-rides-a-Skoolie.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;We had to apply new Eterna-Bond take around the Lexan Skylites after the paint was dry.&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/assets/images/Skoolie-new-paint-new-marker-lights.jpg&quot; data-lightbox=&quot;skoolie-5&quot; data-title=&quot;Painting the roof of our Skoolie was not as bad as we thought it might be.&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/Skoolie-new-paint-new-marker-lights.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Painting the roof of our Skoolie was not as bad as we thought it might be.&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;skoolie-roof-painting-tips&quot;&gt;Skoolie Roof Painting Tips&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use Rust-Oleum white paint.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do not thin or add anything to the paint.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sand and clean the surface really well.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use foam rollers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rent a 7’ high section of scaffolding.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DO NOT believe the weather reports.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 26 Apr 2018 20:57:32 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/upgrades/skoolie-painted-with-rust-oleum/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/upgrades/skoolie-painted-with-rust-oleum/</guid>
        
        
        <category>upgrades</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Skoolie Insurance Tips</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Skoolie insurance is the hardest thing to deal with. It was the one thing we didn’t think would be a big problem. However it turned out to be a major pain in the butt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;tip-1-dont-talk-about-skoolie-insurance&quot;&gt;TIP #1: Don’t talk about Skoolie Insurance&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a rule most insurance companies will &lt;strong&gt;NOT&lt;/strong&gt; insure a converted school bus. &lt;strong&gt;Good Sam&lt;/strong&gt; is the one most people seem to use for Skoolie insurance. We use them and they are okay. To be &lt;strong&gt;100%&lt;/strong&gt; accurate we are insured through &lt;a href=&quot;https://nationalgeneral.com&quot;&gt;National General insurance&lt;/a&gt;. I am happy that we are legal to drive on the road. For now that is good enough. There are other &lt;a href=&quot;https://skoolieinsurance.com&quot;&gt;Skoolie friendly insurance companies&lt;/a&gt; popping up here and there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;tip-2-presentation-is-everything&quot;&gt;Tip #2: Presentation is everything!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Good Sam&lt;/strong&gt; wanted to see the bus, that means pictures. They were willing to insure a partial conversion, which is a plus. The mistake most people make is they don’t “&lt;em&gt;stage&lt;/em&gt;” the photos.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My background is in home plan websites. I can tell you every photo gallery of a house plan has been heavily staged. Some go as far as bringing in all new furniture just for the photos.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We got our conversion to a point where the major layout was complete. Our choice of style was very minimal which helped. Then we cleaned and staged the photos as best we could.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[gallery link=”file” size=”medium” ids=”410,411,409,408,406,404,403,402,401”]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The point is, don’t show a bucket with a toilet seat on it for a bathroom. Put some effort into it. That is what they want to see, that you have made, and are making concrete steps to convert the bus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;tip-3-it-is-all-about-the-implication&quot;&gt;Tip #3: It is all about the implication!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What and how you show things maters. We showed a finished counter with a sink and faucet. We did &lt;strong&gt;NOT&lt;/strong&gt; show under the sink. Why? Because at that time there was no plumbing installed. Same with the cook top. Sure it is installed but there is no propane run to it yet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;gallery-wrapper&quot;&gt;
        &lt;div class=&quot;gallery-box&quot;&gt;
          &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/images/finished-cook-top-counter.jpg&quot; data-lightbox=&quot;skoolie-original&quot; data-title=&quot;Our counter with the propane cooktop installed.&quot;&gt;
          &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/finished-cook-top-counter.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Skoolie counter with the propane cooktop installed.&quot; /&gt;
          &lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;

        &lt;div class=&quot;gallery-box&quot;&gt;
          &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/images/finished-fridge-and-sink-counter-2.jpg&quot; data-lightbox=&quot;skoolie-original&quot; data-title=&quot;Sink counter with the Kee Lite fittings and our 12v refrigerator. &quot;&gt;
          &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/finished-fridge-and-sink-counter-2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Sink counter with the Kee Lite fittings and our 12v refrigerator.&quot; /&gt;
          &lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;

        &lt;div class=&quot;gallery-box&quot;&gt;
          &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/images/finished-sink-and-fridge-counter.jpg&quot; data-lightbox=&quot;skoolie-original&quot; data-title=&quot;Another view of the sink countertop with the Kee Lite fittings hold up the fridge.&quot;&gt;
          &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/finished-sink-and-fridge-counter.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Another view of the sink countertop in our Skoolie with the Kee Lite fittings hold up the fridge.&quot; /&gt;
          &lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;

        &lt;div class=&quot;gallery-box&quot;&gt;
          &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/images/Skoolie-simplified-building-project.jpg&quot; data-lightbox=&quot;skoolie-original&quot; data-title=&quot;Our Skoolie design and layout was centered around simplicity and speed of conversion.&quot;&gt;
          &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/Skoolie-simplified-building-project.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Our Skoolie design and layout was centered around simplicity and speed of conversion.&quot; /&gt;
          &lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;

        &lt;div class=&quot;gallery-box&quot;&gt;
          &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/images/Skoolie-simple-beds.jpg&quot; data-lightbox=&quot;skoolie-original&quot; data-title=&quot;Our Skoolie was designed with two beds.&quot;&gt;
          &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/Skoolie-simple-beds.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Our Skoolie was designed with two beds.&quot; /&gt;
          &lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;

        &lt;div class=&quot;gallery-box&quot;&gt;
          &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/images/Skoolie-simple-bath-tub.jpg&quot; data-lightbox=&quot;skoolie-original&quot; data-title=&quot;Our Skoolie has a very simple and easy to install and use shower.&quot;&gt;
          &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/Skoolie-simple-bath-tub.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Our Skoolie has a very simple and easy to install and use shower.&quot; /&gt;
          &lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you show it looking completed the image will imply that it is functional. The important thing is to make sure it “&lt;em&gt;looks&lt;/em&gt;” like it is completed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;tip-4-can-we-be-honest&quot;&gt;Tip #4: Can we be Honest?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even though we did rely heavily on presentation and the implication, we also kept it real. We told the people at &lt;strong&gt;Good Sam&lt;/strong&gt; that we had not yet installed the tanks. We included photos of the tanks to show we had made the investment and were ready to complete the conversion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/assets/images/Skoolie-tanks-realy-for-installation.jpg&quot; data-lightbox=&quot;skoolie-painting&quot; data-title=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;960&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/Skoolie-tanks-realy-for-installation.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Skoolie insurance - tanks ready for installation&quot; width=&quot;450&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We made it clear that in order to complete the conversion we need to drive the bus to the fabricator so he could install the tanks. It is an all to familiar Catch &lt;strong&gt;22&lt;/strong&gt; situation most Skoolies run into at some point.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;tip-5-you-are-what-you-is&quot;&gt;Tip #5: You are what you is!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t try and game the system. Tell the insurance company exactly what you intend to do with the Skoolie. In our case we use it as a true RV. We take weekend trips and long vacations in it. Some day we might live in it full time. But for now, we make sure the insurance company knows whats what. The last thing you need is to be denied coverage because you misrepresented yourself in an attempt to get cheap Skoolie insurance.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 15 Mar 2018 20:57:32 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/making-it-legal/skoolie-insurance-tips/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/making-it-legal/skoolie-insurance-tips/</guid>
        
        
        <category>making-it-legal</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Skoolie Counter Building Simplified</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Skoolie counters are always a challenge to build. You have the room for the depth but the height can be a problem. And the biggest problem is we have never done this before. Not just the building but living with the counters is a new experience. So how do we know what will work or what we will like?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your kitchen counter is about &lt;strong&gt;2&lt;/strong&gt; feet deep. On a Skoolie you can keep that same depth. However your typical kitchen counters are a lot higher than the height of a school bus window. Some people build the counters the same height as in their house kitchens. But that is a mistake.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;counter-hight-is-an-issue&quot;&gt;Counter Hight is an Issue&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A school bus is designed to have the windows replaced easily. This is a vehicle designed around utility. With a screwdriver and a little elbow grease you can remove a window in a few minutes. Once the screws are removed that hold it in place, the bottom of the window kicks inward and the window comes out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/assets/images/skoolie-cocking-the-windows.jpg&quot; data-lightbox=&quot;skoolie-windows&quot; data-title=&quot;Skoolie counters and windows need to work together&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/skoolie-cocking-the-windows.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Skoolie counters and windows need to work together&quot; width=&quot;550&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you build tall counters that block the bottom of the window you will not be able to remove the window without taking the counter and cabinets out first. Your window glass doesn’t need to break to need to remove it. If the window latch breaks, and they fail all the time, they can be fix and replaced easily, &lt;strong&gt;AFTER&lt;/strong&gt; the window is removed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;skoolie-counter--cabinet-weight&quot;&gt;Skoolie Counter &amp;amp; Cabinet Weight&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Typical kitchen cabinets are strong sturdy heavy units. In a house weight is not an issue. However in a Skoolie weight should be a concern. Sure a school bus is a truck and can carry somewhere around &lt;strong&gt;8000&lt;/strong&gt; pounds (&lt;em&gt;depending on your bus&lt;/em&gt;). Just because it can doesn’t mean it should.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/assets/images/counters-ready-for-paint.jpg&quot; data-lightbox=&quot;skoolie-painting&quot; data-title=&quot;Skoolie counters kept light and simple&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/counters-ready-for-paint.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Skoolie counters kept light and simple&quot; width=&quot;550&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Keeping the counters and cabinets as light as possible will help with fuel economy, performance, and safety. A Skoolie is a bit top heavy, adding lots and lots of weight above the floor line can make the bus less stable. A heavy bus doesn’t perform well, and we all know Skoolies are not big on performance. More importantly the lighter a bus is the better the fuel economy will be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/assets/images/kee-klamps-under-counter.jpg&quot; data-lightbox=&quot;skoolie-image-1&quot; data-title=&quot;Skoolie counters during construction&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/kee-klamps-under-counter.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Skoolie counters during construction&quot; width=&quot;550&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/assets/images/counter-wall-bracket.jpg&quot; data-lightbox=&quot;skoolie-image-1&quot; data-title=&quot;Skoolie counter mount brace&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/counter-wall-bracket.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Skoolie counter mount brace&quot; width=&quot;550&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;why-kee-lite&quot;&gt;Why Kee Lite?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/assets/images/simplified-building-supplies.jpg&quot; data-lightbox=&quot;skoolie-supplies&quot; data-title=&quot;Skoolie counters made with Lee Lite&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/simplified-building-supplies.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Skoolie counters made with Lee Lite&quot; width=&quot;550&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In order to keep our Skoolie counters light, adjustable and strong we went with aluminum pipe and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.simplifiedbuilding.com/pipe-fittings/kee-lite&quot;&gt;Kee Lite fittings&lt;/a&gt;. The counters are at the height of the windows, for us that is 30 inches. The &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.simplifiedbuilding.com/pipe-fittings/kee-lite&quot;&gt;Kee Lite fittings&lt;/a&gt; from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.simplifiedbuilding.com&quot;&gt;Simplified Building&lt;/a&gt; made the job of building these counters very easy. Nothing in the bus is really level or straight. With this building system we can adjust things &lt;strong&gt;AFTER&lt;/strong&gt; they are cut.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;gallery-wrapper&quot;&gt;
        &lt;div class=&quot;gallery-box&quot;&gt;
          &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/images/finished-cook-top-counter.jpg&quot; data-lightbox=&quot;skoolie-original&quot; data-title=&quot;Our counter with the propane cooktop installed.&quot;&gt;
          &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/finished-cook-top-counter.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Skoolie counter with the propane cooktop installed.&quot; /&gt;
          &lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;

        &lt;div class=&quot;gallery-box&quot;&gt;
          &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/images/finished-fridge-and-sink-counter-2.jpg&quot; data-lightbox=&quot;skoolie-original&quot; data-title=&quot;Sink counter with the Kee Lite fittings and our 12v refrigerator. &quot;&gt;
          &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/finished-fridge-and-sink-counter-2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Sink counter with the Kee Lite fittings and our 12v refrigerator.&quot; /&gt;
          &lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;

        &lt;div class=&quot;gallery-box&quot;&gt;
          &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/images/finished-sink-and-fridge-counter.jpg&quot; data-lightbox=&quot;skoolie-original&quot; data-title=&quot;Another view of the sink countertop with the Kee Lite fittings hold up the fridge.&quot;&gt;
          &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/finished-sink-and-fridge-counter.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Another view of the sink countertop in our Skoolie with the Kee Lite fittings hold up the fridge.&quot; /&gt;
          &lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;

        &lt;div class=&quot;gallery-box&quot;&gt;
          &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/images/fridge-sink-counters.jpg&quot; data-lightbox=&quot;skoolie-original&quot; data-title=&quot;The sink counter during construction of our Skoolie.&quot;&gt;
          &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/fridge-sink-counters.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;he sink counter during construction of our Skoolie.&quot; /&gt;
          &lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our counters are extremely strong and more importantly they are silent. A Skoolie rides like a truck, because that is what it is. Even with the rough ride our counters don’t make a sound.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;gallery-wrapper&quot;&gt;
        &lt;div class=&quot;gallery-box&quot;&gt;
          &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/images/sink-and-fridge-counters.jpg&quot; data-lightbox=&quot;skoolie-original-1&quot; data-title=&quot;Simplified Building's Kee Lite fittings were are blessing during construction.&quot;&gt;
          &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/sink-and-fridge-counters.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Simplified Building's Kee Lite fittings were are blessing during construction.&quot; /&gt;
          &lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;

        &lt;div class=&quot;gallery-box&quot;&gt;
          &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/images/Counters-installed.jpg&quot; data-lightbox=&quot;skoolie-original-1&quot; data-title=&quot;Both of the counters in our Skoolie during construction.&quot;&gt;
          &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/Counters-installed.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Both of the counters in our Skoolie during construction.&quot; /&gt;
          &lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;

        &lt;div class=&quot;gallery-box&quot;&gt;
          &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/images/cook-top-counter-for-travel.jpg&quot; data-lightbox=&quot;skoolie-original-1&quot; data-title=&quot;The cooktop counter with the cover closed on the cooktop.&quot;&gt;
          &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/cook-top-counter-for-travel.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;he cooktop counter with the cover closed on the cooktop.&quot; /&gt;
          &lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;

        &lt;div class=&quot;gallery-box&quot;&gt;
          &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/images/Skoolie-simplified-building-project.jpg&quot; data-lightbox=&quot;skoolie-original-1&quot; data-title=&quot;Our Skoolie design and layout was centered around simplicity and speed of conversion.&quot;&gt;
          &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/Skoolie-simplified-building-project.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Our Skoolie design and layout was centered around simplicity and speed of conversion.&quot; /&gt;
          &lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;we-dont-know-what-we-want&quot;&gt;We Don’t Know What We Want!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After our first trip in the bus we learned a lot about what we like. Having never lived in a Skoolie before there was a lot to learn. We found that the lower counter height was &lt;strong&gt;NOT&lt;/strong&gt; an issue. After the first day you don’t notice it at all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/assets/images/Cooking-on-kee-klamp-counter.jpg&quot; data-lightbox=&quot;skoolie-counter&quot; data-title=&quot;Cooking on our counter supported by Kee Lite fixtures.&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/Cooking-on-kee-klamp-counter.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Skoolie counter in action&quot; width=&quot;550&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However we are thinking of making some adjustments and changes to our layout. Thankfully the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.simplifiedbuilding.com/pipe-fittings/kee-lite&quot;&gt;Kee Lite system&lt;/a&gt; allows us to quickly and easily take things down and move them around. If we had built house-type kitchen cabinets we would be looking at major work to make just a few small changes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;a-cow-dont-make-ham&quot;&gt;A Cow Don’t Make Ham!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A Skoolie is a bus, which is a truck. It is not a cabin or a house. It will never ride as nice as a real &lt;strong&gt;RV&lt;/strong&gt;. It will never be as warm (&lt;em&gt;or cool&lt;/em&gt;) as an &lt;strong&gt;RV&lt;/strong&gt;. But if you put function over form you will have a very comfortable space to live in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our goal was to have a bus that Abides. One that doesn’t pretend to be anything other than what it is. One that was as comfortable, safe, and economical as it could be. Thanks to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.simplifiedbuilding.com/pipe-fittings/kee-lite&quot;&gt;Kee Lite&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.simplifiedbuilding.com&quot;&gt;Simplified Building&lt;/a&gt; we think we are getting close to that goal. But that’s like, our opinion, man.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 15 Feb 2018 19:57:32 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/skoolie/skoolie-counter-building-simplified/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/skoolie/skoolie-counter-building-simplified/</guid>
        
        
        <category>skoolie</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Fixing the Flashers in a Skoolie</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Not everything worked in our &lt;strong&gt;1995&lt;/strong&gt; Thomas school bus when we got it. But enough was working correctly to get her on the road fairly quickly. There were a few things that when fixed would make it safer, and not to mention much more enjoyable to drive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first thing we tested when we got the bus was the lights. The headlights (&lt;em&gt;high and low beam&lt;/em&gt;), parking lights, running lights, marker lights and blinkers all worked fine. On the outside they worked, but the dash was another subject.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All the important things on the dash worked fine. What didn’t work was the back-lights. At night the left side of the dash was dark. The left-side blinker indicator on the dash was also on the fritz.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When driving during the day (&lt;em&gt;or at night&lt;/em&gt;) I would use the round mirror on the nose to see if my blinkers were on. It was the only way to tell if the left blinker was working. With the blinkers running the normal “&lt;em&gt;ticking&lt;/em&gt;” noise was almost impossible to hear.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We drove it like this for a good &lt;strong&gt;2000&lt;/strong&gt; miles. Then the blinkers started acting very strangely. Normally blinkers will speed up if one of the lights is blown. However this time our blinkers were flashing so fast I was afraid they were going to cause people seizures. But all the bulbs were flashing, no burned out lights.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;flashers-must-be-fixed&quot;&gt;Flashers Must Be Fixed&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After doing some digging we figured it was the flasher relay. Luckily this relay is located in the main fuse panel on the dash. The original flasher relay was round. These relays burned out quickly and they were replaced with a square relay. So that leaves us with a square peg in a round hole.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/assets/images/old-and-new-flasher-relays.jpg&quot; data-lightbox=&quot;skoolie-image-1&quot; data-title=&quot;New flasher relay doesn't quite fit inside the fusebox.&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/old-and-new-flasher-relays.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Old and New Flasher Relays in a Skoolie&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our bus had a square relay so it was not original. The &lt;strong&gt;U.S. Navy&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.govplanet.com&quot;&gt;the last owner&lt;/a&gt;) had replaced the relay with a really cheap unit. The local &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.wallaceinternational.com&quot;&gt;International truck dealer&lt;/a&gt; hooked us up with a new, larger, louder, stronger flasher relay. That got the blinkers flashing at a normal speed, and I could now hear the clicking sound of the indicators.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;fixing-the-dash-indicator&quot;&gt;Fixing the Dash Indicator&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To fix the indicator light on the dash we had to remove the unit. The International &lt;strong&gt;3800&lt;/strong&gt; instrument cluster comes out fairly simply. There are two screws located on the bottom of the dash. Remove those and then push two tabs located on the top and the dash will tilt out from the top.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/assets/images/screws-to-remove-to-take-out-the-Skoolie-dash.jpg&quot; data-lightbox=&quot;skoolie-image-1&quot; data-title=&quot;Only two screws hole the instrument cluster onto the dashboard of the Skoolie.&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/screws-to-remove-to-take-out-the-Skoolie-dash.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Removing a Skoolie Dash&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You have to disconnect two electrical connections on the back, one on the left and one on the right. You will also have to disconnect two air connections, if you have air brakes. Make sure you remember where the green air line goes and where the red line goes. The last connection is the oil pressure line, I didn’t disconnect this as I could get to what I needed without totally removing the cluster.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/assets/images/Skoolie-Dash-removed.jpg&quot; data-lightbox=&quot;skoolie-image-1&quot; data-title=&quot;With the screws removed, you press the tabs on the top and the cluster tilts forward enough to disconnect the stuff in the back.&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/Skoolie-Dash-removed.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Removing the Dash of a Skoolie&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;which-bulbs-to-use&quot;&gt;Which Bulbs to Use?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My burned out bulbs didn’t have any markings on them so I had to guess what they were. I found that the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/SYLVANIA-Long-Miniature-Contains-Bulbs/dp/B00318V1BU&quot;&gt;Sylvania #73 and the #74&lt;/a&gt; bulbs both worked fine. Removing the bulbs requires you to twist the base, they sound like they are breaking but they came out and went back in fine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/assets/images/dash-light-bulbs.png&quot; data-lightbox=&quot;skoolie-image-1&quot; data-title=&quot;Dash bulbs for the 3800 International dash.&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/dash-light-bulbs.png&quot; alt=&quot;Dash Builds for a Skoolie&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Putting everything back together was not too bad. It was all well worth the effort the first time I turned on the left blinker and could see the indicator on the dash flashing at me. It is the little things that make me happy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/assets/images/Skoolie-dash-indicator-light.jpg&quot; data-lightbox=&quot;skoolie-image-1&quot; data-title=&quot;New light bulbs installed and cluster put back the blinker indicator is working again!&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/Skoolie-dash-indicator-light.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Working flasher indicator on a Skoolie dash&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With all things bus related one fix has caused another problem. When the dash was removed the &lt;strong&gt;23&lt;/strong&gt; year old glue let go in places. The plastic is brittle and the glue failed in a few spots. On either side of the dash there are indicator and warning lights. The strip of colored plastic with text on it came undone. It was very difficult getting the dash back in with all the parts flopping around and falling out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/assets/images/dash-warning-lights-slipped-down.jpg&quot; data-lightbox=&quot;skoolie-image-1&quot; data-title=&quot;The instrument cluster will have to come back out again, it moved during installation&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/dash-warning-lights-slipped-down.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Broken Dash on a 1995 Skoolie&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We will have to remove the dash a second time and re-glue these panels. Both the left and the right sides have slipped down a quarter inch. Now the text no longer lines up with the indicator bulbs. But that is the way it goes with a Skoolie, fixing one thing can cause two new problems. The project is never truly finished. But that is one reason we love them.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 11 Feb 2018 19:57:32 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/skoolie/fixing-the-flashers-in-a-skoolie/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/skoolie/fixing-the-flashers-in-a-skoolie/</guid>
        
        
        <category>skoolie</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Skoolie Build Deadline</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;If you don’t set a deadline you’ll never finish. That is what we found. After working on our Skoolie for a year we were not as finished as we wanted to be. So we set a deadline and worked hard to meet it.&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Back in February of &lt;strong&gt;2017&lt;/strong&gt; we celebrated our first year of ownership of a school bus. We did that by finally getting insurance and a license plate. We had worked on the bus for a year never driving it more than up and down our street.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The speed at which the year had gone by scared us. The bus was far from finished. With plates and insurance we started taking the bus on day trips to the beach. It was nice but without running water or a working toilet it was just fancy shade.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/assets/images/skoolie-at-the-beach.jpg&quot; data-lightbox=&quot;skoolie-beach&quot; data-title=&quot;Our Skoolie was fun for a day but without it being finished it was not too much fun at the beach.&quot;&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter wp-image-309 size-full&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/skoolie-at-the-beach.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Our Skoolie parked on the beach at Sanibel Island causeway&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That was when we read about the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.greatamericaneclipse.com&quot;&gt;eclipse that was happening in August 21, 2017&lt;/a&gt;. Being only about &lt;strong&gt;700&lt;/strong&gt; miles away from the path of the total eclipse we set a goal of being there. The race was on to finish the bus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;we-had-all-the-parts-time-to-install-them-all&quot;&gt;We Had All the Parts, Time to Install Them All&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While we had all the tanks we needed they were not installed. Because they would be heavy, and &lt;strong&gt;explosive&lt;/strong&gt; when filled, we decided to sub that work out to a professional. The bus was dropped off at a local friend’s shop who is a master welder and fabricator. It took about 2 weeks, he was very busy, but we finally had our tanks installed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/assets/images/All-the-new-tanks.jpg&quot; data-lightbox=&quot;skoolie-image-tanks2&quot; data-title=&quot;Our tanks under our Skoolie, professional mounted.&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/All-the-new-tanks.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Skoolie Build Deadline - tanks under the bus installed&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For a year we had been gathering parts and pieces, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B002XM5G70/ref=oh_aui_detailpage_o05_s01?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;psc=1&quot;&gt;water pump&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B001P6FTHC/ref=oh_aui_detailpage_o02_s01?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;psc=1&quot;&gt;fuse boxes&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B01DXD0UF0/ref=oh_aui_detailpage_o02_s01?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;psc=1&quot;&gt;12v power outlets&lt;/a&gt;. Now we had to dig through the piles of boxes in the house and start installing all this. Because we have no experience doing this, each system and each project started with learning what the hell it does and how the hell to install it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Par for the course about &lt;strong&gt;10%&lt;/strong&gt; of the stuff I got was either the wrong size or the wrong thing altogether. Which meant more panicked trips to the hardware store and overnight shipping from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com&quot;&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt;. I think it is fair to say we have enough small parts leftover to start a second school bus project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/assets/images/trips-to-home-depot.jpg&quot; data-lightbox=&quot;skoolie-homedepot&quot; data-title=&quot;Every project on our Skoolie requires at LEAST 2 or 3 trips to the hardware store.&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/trips-to-home-depot.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Skoolie Build Deadline - Shopping at Home Depot&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At some point money became meaningless. I think it was the fourth or fifth trip to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.homedepot.com&quot;&gt;Home Depot&lt;/a&gt; for &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.homedepot.com/s/sharkbite?NCNI-5&quot;&gt;SharkBite plumbing parts&lt;/a&gt;. That was when it went from a simple project, to a mission that everything, and everyone would be sacrificed for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;progress-must-be-made&quot;&gt;Progress Must Be Made!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We tried to make progress everyday. It was a priority to get something done everyday, no matter how small progress must be made everyday. This was hard because almost every task usually required at least one trip to the hardware store.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/assets/images/make-progress-on-the-abide-bus.jpg&quot; data-lightbox=&quot;skoolie-image-1&quot; data-title=&quot;The results of constant effort to make some sort of progress every day of the week.&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/make-progress-on-the-abide-bus.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Skoolie Build Deadline - Progress must be made everyday&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Trying to find a longer bolt for the Lithium battery was a &lt;strong&gt;4 hour ordeal&lt;/strong&gt;. Ester visited more than half a dozen stores. I made phone calls, and visited countless websites. In the end the bolts had to come from Germany, but that is a story for another time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-skoolie-is-never-finished&quot;&gt;The Skoolie is Never Finished&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It seemed that as soon as we got one system finished we realized the bus needed just one more thing. Adding shelves and storage areas was a weekly event for a while there. In the end we had to say enough! It is good enough for now. Otherwise we would have just kept making more changes and additions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When faced with a hard deadline you tend to focus more clearly. Things we struggled with like the shower curtain, shower drain, sink drain, and the battery placement were figured out quickly. Without the deadline we’d still be debating the best way to run the sink drain, and about a dozen other things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/assets/images/The-Finished-Shower-tub.jpg&quot; data-lightbox=&quot;skoolie-shower&quot; data-title=&quot;We used a water troff from the local tractor store as a shower basin, the water pump is mounted next to it.&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/The-Finished-Shower-tub.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Skoolie Build Deadline - The finished shower and bath tub&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also became more comfortable with accepting our level of workmanship. We always fall short of our vision of the finished product. In the end we tempered our disappointment with our workmanship with the satisfaction of creating a finished, working system. When we turned on the water faucet on the kitchen sink and water came out, and drained into the gray water tank. We, in our own minds, became &lt;strong&gt;Master Plumbers!!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;last-minute-skoolie-customizations&quot;&gt;Last Minute Skoolie Customizations&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Time slipped away and we found ourselves one day before leaving. We had not got the propane tank filled yet. When I took the bus to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.loves.com&quot;&gt;Love’s truck stop&lt;/a&gt; to get it filled, I discovered the fill connection to the tank was not reachable with a standard &lt;strong&gt;RV&lt;/strong&gt; fill gun.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I raced to &lt;strong&gt;Home Depot&lt;/strong&gt; and immediately drew a blank on how I was going to build a door. I had one chance to buy all the parts I’ll need and until sundown to build it. When you have a Skoolie you spend a &lt;strong&gt;LOT&lt;/strong&gt; off time wandering the isles of Home Depot and Lowe’s mumbling to yourself. You have to find things that are not designed to be used how you need them to be used. You build things in your mind, and hope they work in reality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/assets/images/propane-door-closed.jpg&quot; data-lightbox=&quot;skoolie-Door-1&quot; data-title=&quot;The door to access the propane tank was made the day before we left, we could not fill the propane tank without it.&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/propane-door-closed.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Skoolie Build Deadline - New Propane door closed&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/assets/images/propane-door-open.jpg&quot; data-lightbox=&quot;skoolie-Door-1&quot; data-title=&quot;Now the propane tank's fill port can be accessed by any facility that fills RV propane tanks.&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/propane-door-open.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Skoolie Build Deadline - Propane door open&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the end we managed to make a decent functional door for accessing the propane tank. The tank was filled but we didn’t have time to test the 2 burner cook-top. We had to deal with that the first time we needed to use it. &lt;strong&gt;SPOILER ALERT!&lt;/strong&gt; It worked just great!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/assets/images/First-use-of-cooktop.jpg&quot; data-lightbox=&quot;skoolie-cooking&quot; data-title=&quot;Our first meal cooked in the bus, after some propane pressure adjustments it worked great!&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/First-use-of-cooktop.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Skoolie Build Deadline - Using the propane cooktop for the first time&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was just &lt;strong&gt;18&lt;/strong&gt; hours after I was wandering around Home Depot looking for parts when we were all packed and heading out-of-town. We were back at the Love’s truck stopped filling the fuel tank and getting some snacks for the road. That was when the bus didn’t want to start. We didn’t know it then, but that was the real start of our adventure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/assets/images/abide-bus-camping.jpg&quot; data-lightbox=&quot;skoolie-image-1&quot; data-title=&quot;Our Skoolie parked at the Hartwell Lake camp ground in Hartwell GA.&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/abide-bus-camping.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Skoolie Build Deadline - The adventure was just beginning &quot; width=&quot;600&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 20 Oct 2017 20:57:32 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/skoolie/skoolie-build-deadline/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/skoolie/skoolie-build-deadline/</guid>
        
        
        <category>skoolie</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
